(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
幾つの苦も美観主義
How many pains of aestheticism
愛の反戦一人じゃんけん
A love rock-paper-scissors, playing alone
運命と縛り見ない振り
Pretending not to see fate and restrictions
それも暗転
That too, turns dark
Now I know all about you, babe
I don't want the handbags, the money, or the diamond rings
'Cause guys like you they all don't care about the little things
まぁ anyway 吹っ切れた訳で
Well, anyway, I think I got over this
棒に当たって吠えたって圏外です
Barking after hitting a dead end is out of the question
I'm moving on and I'm never ever turning back around, around, around again
Now I'll go higher and I'll go higher
And you couldn't take me down if you tried
ばら撒いてた愛取返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I showered over you and retreating
Now I can finally open my eyes
そんで来世もっかい君への返品サイン
And then, a return sign for you in my next life
Getcha out my life boy
Getcha out of my life, boy
I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
Departure!
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
you awaken,
天使の微笑みで 連れ出して!
take me away with an angel's smile!
孤独でも 一人じゃないさ
Even if you're lonely, you're not alone.
生まれてきたことに 必ず意味がある
There is surely a reason for being born.
優しさに満ち溢れてる
Overflowing with kindness,
青い地球（ほし）にありがとう
thank you to the blue planet.
YOU CAN SMILE AGAIN!
太陽を浴びて
Bask in the sun.
YOU CAN FLY AWAY!
世界中が君の輝きを待ってる
The whole world is waiting for your radiance.
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
you awaken,
天使の微笑みで 連れ出して!
take me away with an angel's smile!
YOU CAN SMILE!
始まりはいつでも遅くないさ
It's never too late to start.
何度でも立ち上がれ!
Stand up again and again!
最後まであきらめないさ
I won't give up until the end.
やり続けることに必ず意味がある
There is surely meaning in continuing.
YOU JUST TRY AGAIN!
闇を抜けて
Escape from the darkness.
YOU JUST GO AWAY!
未来はいつも僕たちを待ってる
The future is always waiting for us.
大空駆け抜けて
Run through the vast sky,
海原越えて行け
go across the ocean.
天使の投げキッス つかまえて!
Catch the angel's blown kiss!
YOU CAN TRY!
まだ誰も見たことない世界へ
To a world no one has ever seen before.
好きになって もっと
Please like me more,
私を見て もっと
look at me even more.
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes met.
ハート作って 恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and please fall in love with me.
やれること 何でもします
I'll do anything I can,
NGなしで 体当たり挑戦
with no 'no-go's,' giving it my all.
エゴサで見つけた アンチのコメ
Antis' comments I found by ego-searching...
ふざけんな 誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me, I know better than anyone.
でも大丈夫 ここに立てば みんながいる
But it's okay, because when I stand here, you're all with me.
いくよ！
Here I go!
好きになって もっと
Please like me more,
私を見て もっと
look at me even more.
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love!
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you more,
夢を見せる もっと
show you more dreams.
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Please have fun on this special night full of love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング
Take into your heart my self-indulgent love song
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna fan-service you!
はぁ…終わりが近づく
Ah... The end is near...
寂しいな
I'm so sad...
嬉しいな
But I'm happy!
君に 愛のビームを あげるよ！
I'll cast a beam of love to you!
約束！
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words overflowing with kindness,
心無い誰かの言葉さえも
and even the heartless words of someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ
They're both necessary, necessary,
強くなろう
to become stronger.
好きに叫べ！もっと！
Shout as you like! More!
楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Enjoy yourself! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, I hope it becomes a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと
Let's sing together forever.
共に歩もう ずっと
Let's walk together forever.
合言葉は とびきりの L・O・V・E
The password is an extraordinary L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
My reward to you is a blown kiss full of love.
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでね 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Please enjoy this special night full of love.
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna fan-service you!
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Guitar to Kodoku to Aoi Hoshi
突然降る夕立 あぁ傘もないや嫌
A sudden evening shower, no umbrella, ugh
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
Why would I know how the sky feels?
季節の変わり目の服は 何着りゃいいんだろ
What should I wear for the changing seasons?
春と秋 どこいっちゃったんだよ
Where did spring and autumn go?
息も出来ない 情報の圧力
I can't even breathe, it's the pressure of info
めまいの螺旋だ わたしはどこにいる
A spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
Even though I can hear my own breathing clearly
変だね 世界の音がしない
It's strange, I can't hear the world's sounds
足りない 足りない 誰にも聞かせられない
It's not enough, I can't let anyone hear it
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I shouted, unable to even make scribbled sounds
ありのままなんて 誰に見せるんだ
To whom should I show my true self?
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
A fool like me just keeps on singing
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I just vent it all to the stars?
エリクサーに貼り替える作業も 何となくなんだ
Changing strings to Elixirs is just something I do
欠けた爪を少し触る
I lightly touch my chipped fingernail
半径300ミリの体で 必死に鳴いてる
With this 300mm body, I'm crying out
音楽に取っちゃ ここが地球だな
To music, this must be what Earth is
空気を吸い込んで 空を殴るよ
I'll breathe in and strike at the sky
なんにも出来ない 私は無力さ
I can't do anything, I'm so powerless
だけどさ その手で この弦を弾いたら
But if I pluck these strings with these hands...
何かが変わって見えたような
It felt like something began to change
眩しい 眩しい そんなに光るなよ
It's too bright, too bright, don't shine like that
私のダサい影が より濃くなってしまうだろ
My uncool shadow will only grow darker
なんでこんな熱くなっちゃってんだ 止まらない
Why have I become so heated? I can't stop
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
A fool like me just keeps on singing
うるさいんだって 心臓
My heart is just too loud
蒼い惑星 独りぼっち
A blue planet, all alone
いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
I've listened to so many sounds
回り続けて幾億年
Billions of years spent spinning...
一瞬...
A single moment...
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet
聞いて、聴けよ
Listen, hear me out
私 私 私はここにいる
I, I, I am here
殴り書きみたいな音
With sounds like scribbles,
出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed while I couldn't let them out
なんかになりたい なりたい
I want to become something, I want to be...
何者かであっても
...someone, whoever it may be
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Foolish me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
ハロ／ハワユ
Hello/How are you
ハロ
Hello
窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
I open my window and whisper quietly
ハワユ
How are you?
誰もいない 部屋で一人
In a room all by myself
モーニン
Morning
朝が来たよ
Morning has come,
土砂降りの朝が
a morning of downpouring rain
チックタック
Tick-tock
私のネジを
Someone, please...
誰か巻いて
...wind up my spring
ハロ
Hello
昔のアニメに そんなのいたっけな
Was there someone like that in an old anime?
ハワユ
How are you?
羨ましいな みんなに愛されて
I'm so jealous, being loved by everyone
スリーピン
Sleeping
馬鹿なこと言ってないで 支度をしなくちゃ
Stop saying silly things and get ready
クライン
Crying
涙の跡を隠すため
To hide the traces of my tears
もう 口癖になった『まぁいっか』
'Oh well' has become my catchphrase
昨日の言葉がふと頭をよぎる
Yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind
『もう君には全然期待してないから』
'I'm not expecting anything from you anymore'
そりゃまぁ私だって 自分に期待などしてないけれど
Well, even I don't expect anything from myself
アレは一体どういうつもりですか
But what on earth did you mean by that?
喉元まで出かかった言葉
The words that were on the tip of my tongue
口を突いて出たのは嘘
What came out of my mouth was a lie
こうして今日も私は貴重な
And so today as well, I continue to live...
言葉を浪費して生きていく
...wasting these precious words
何故隠してしまうのですか
Why do you hide it away?
笑われるのが怖いのですか
Are you afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか
Do you not want to see anyone?
それ本当ですか
Is that really true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて
Drowning in a sea called 'ambiguity'
息も出来ないほど苦しいの
It's so painful I can't even breathe
少し声が聞きたくなりました
I've started to want to hear your voice a little
本当に弱いな
I'm really so weak
一向に進まない支度の途中
In the middle of getting ready, making no progress
朦朧とした頭で思う
I think with a hazy head
もう理由をつけて休んでしまおうかな
Maybe I should just make an excuse and take the day off
いやいや分かってますって
No, no, I know...
なんとなく言ってみただけだよ
I just said it for no particular reason
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't be mad
幸せだろうと 不幸せだろうと
Whether I'm happy or unhappy
平等に残酷に朝日は昇る
The morning sun rises equally and cruelly
生きてるだけで精一杯の私に
For me, who's doing my best just to stay alive
これ以上何を望むというの
What more do you want from me?
何故気にしてしまうのですか
Why do you care so much?
Thank you, ありがとうと言いたいの
Thank you, I want to say thank you
Thank you, ありがとうと言いたいよ
Thank you, 一度だけでもいいから
Thank you, even if it's just once
心の底から　恩を刻みながら　ありがとうと言いたいの
With deep gratitude from my heart, I want to say thank you
なぜ隠してしまうのですか
Why do you hide it away?
本当は聞いて欲しいのですか
Do you actually want someone to listen?
絶対笑ったりしないから
I'll never laugh at you, I promise
話してみませんか
So why don't you try telling me?
口を開かなければ分からない
If you don't open your mouth, I won't know
思ってるだけでは伝わらない
Just thinking it won't convey anything
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう
What a troublesome creature they are
人間というのは
Those called humans
ハロー、ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
you
Composition: dai / Lyrics: 癒月
Composition: dai / Lyrics: Yuzuki
あなたは今　どこで何をしていますか
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where the sky continues?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
The things that filled my heart until now,
失って初めて　気づいた
I lost them and realized for the first time.
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
Just how much you were supporting me,
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
Just how many smiles you gave me.
失ってしまった　代償は
The price I paid for losing them,
とてつもなく　大きすぎて
Is far, far too great.
取り戻そうと　必死に
Desperately trying to take them back,
手を伸ばしても　届かなくて
I reached out my hand, but I couldn't reach them.
まるで　風のように
Just like the wind,
すり抜けて　届きそうで
Slipping through, almost reaching,
届かない
But not quite.
孤独と　絶望に
With loneliness and despair,
胸を締め付けられ
Squeezing my chest,
心が　壊れそうに
My heart is about to break,
なるけれど
But still...
思い出に残る　あなたの笑顔が
The smile of yours that remains in my memories,
私を　いつも励ましてくれる
Always encourages me.
もう一度　あの頃に戻ろう
Let's go back to that time once more.
今度は　きっと大丈夫
Next time, it'll surely be okay.
いつも傍で笑っていよう
Let's always be smiling together,
あなたの　すぐ傍で
Right by your side.
あなたは今　どこで何をしていますか
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where the sky continues?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Will you stay smiling, just like always?
今はただそれを願い続ける
Now I'll just keep on wishing for that.
Departures 〜あなたにおくるアイの歌〜
Departures ~A Love Song for You~
もう あなたから愛されることも
No longer being loved by you,
必要とされることもない
Nor being needed by you...
そして私はこうして一人ぼっちで
And so, here I am, all alone.
あの時あなたはなんて言ったの？
What did you say to me back then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
The unreachable words dance in the air.
想いをわかってるのに
Even though I understand these feelings,
今日もしてしまう
I end up doing it again today—
叶わぬ願いごとを
making a wish that won't come true.
離さないで ギュッと
Don't let go, hold me tight.
手を握り合って
Holding each other's hands,
あなたと二人
together with you,
続くと言って
Tell me it will continue.
繋いだ その手は温かくて
That hand I held was so warm...
温かくて
So warm...
優しかった
and so kind.
あなたはいつも そうやって私を
You always treated me that way,
怒らせて 最後に泣かすんだ
getting me angry, then making me cry in the end.
だけど後になって
But afterwards,
「ごめんね」と言う
you would say "I'm sorry."
その顔 好きだった
I loved that look on your face.
離さないで ギュッと
Don't let go, hold me tight.
そう思いきり
With all my heart,
あなたの手を 握りしめたい
I want to hold your hand.
二人で おでこを合わせながら
As the two of us press our foreheads together,
眠るの
we fall asleep.
もう二度とは 会えないってことは
The fact that we'll never meet again...
知っていたの
I already knew.
離さないで ギュッと
Don't let go, hold me tight.
あなたが好き
I love you.
もう一度だけ
Just one more time,
笑ってくれないの？
won't you smile for me?
あなたの
Before your...
温もりが消えちゃう前に
...warmth completely fades away,
抱きしめて
please hold me.
mumei
忘れてしまった
I remember only...
ことだけを覚えている
...the things I've forgotten.
ぽかりと空いた穴の先で
Beyond the gaping hole that opened up,
君と出会った
I met you.
きっかけで 君と出会った
By chance, I met you.
名前も 顔も
Your name, your face...
分からない君なんだか
I don't know who you are, but...
懐かしいような気がした
I felt a sense of nostalgia.
互いに 穴埋めてゆくように
As if filling each other's voids...
ふざけあって
Messing around,
笑いあって
laughing together.
世界のどこかにいる
Somewhere in the world,
君のため
for your sake...
今 生きているよ
I'm living right now.
僕ら
We are,
無名のまま
remaining nameless.
例えば これが
For example, even if this...
映し出された 幻でも
is just a projected illusion,
確かに 感じる
I definitely feel it,
今 君がそこにいること
that you are there right now.
名前も 顔も わからない君
You, whose name and face I don't know.
サヨナラ してしまえば終わりだ
If we say goodbye, it's the end.
君がいなきゃ 穴は大きくなる
Without you, the void grows bigger.
構わないさ
I don't mind,
すぐ見つかる
I'll find you soon.
世界のどこかにいる
Somewhere in the world...
君はどこ？
Where are you?
今 ここにいるよ
I'm right here.
私
Me,
無名
Mumei.
辺りは一面 真っ暗な世界
The surroundings are a world of darkness,
真っ逆さまに 落ちていく
falling headlong.
無名だから この世界には 忘れられ 消えちゃうの
Because I'm nameless, I'll be forgotten and vanish.
それでも 君が 求めるのなら
Even so, if you seek me out,
この胸に 空いた 穴に今
in the void that opened in this chest now...
君から私へ 風は通り抜ける
the wind passes through from you to me.
希望の鳥が 今 君の元へと行く
The bird of hope is heading to you now.
世界のどこかにいる
Somewhere in the world,
君のため
for your sake...
今 生きていくよ
I will live on now.
私
Me,
無名のまま
remaining nameless.
Visual Production: Kanauru
Planning: Nanashi Mumei / Kanauru / Mooma
Special Thanks To: Hoomans and all those who have supported Mumei over the years
Hoomansのみなさん、
Oh hi hoomans!
この3年半、最後まで支えてくれて本当にありがとうね。
Thank you so much for the last three and a half years.
文章ではきっと、私の気持ちをすべて伝えきれないと思いますが、
Even in writing, I know I won't be able to fully convey my feelings.
本当にみなさんのおかげで、私の人生がとても豊かなものになりました。
You have truly changed my life for the better.
ここから離れていても、どんなことがあっても、みなさんのことを想っています。
Wherever I go, no matter what I face, I will remember you!
みなさんがくれた優しさと支えは、これからもずっと私の心の中にあります。
I will always carry the kindness and support you showed me in my heart.
おかげさまで、想像以上のことがたくさんできました。
I was able to do more than I ever imagined because of you.
この気持ちは、一生忘れません。
I will never forget this feeling!
私がhololiveにいたことが、誰かにとって少しでも力になれたなら、
I hope that my presence in hololive was a good one.
誰かに笑顔を届けられたなら、生きていてよかったと心から思います。
Any moment of joy I might have brought someone makes me even happier to be alive!
それは私にとって、かけがえのない宝物です。
It is an irreplaceable treasure to me.
一緒に過ごしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for being here with me.
思いきりありのままの自分で楽しくいられるあたたかい場所もくれてありがとう。
Thank you for giving me a warm space to be silly and have fun.
そしてNanashi Mumeiでいさせてくれて、本当にありがとう。
Thank you for letting me be Nanashi Mumei.